safaribookings.com 2019-09-30

# Privacy Policy of SafariBookings.com

We highly value your trust in us and will duly and diligently safeguard and protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information.

We highly value your trust in us and will duly and diligently safeguard and protect the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information. 

This privacy policy applies to all of our services, whether accessed or made available online or through any other platform or device (hereafter collectively referred to as the "Site", "site", "Website" or "website"). 

### We don't spam. Period. (When we do and don't send emails)

We won't email you unless you have expressly indicated you want us to. We will only email you in one of the following cases: 

  * You use the password recovery option, where we email you instructions on how to reset your password.
  * You activate the optional feature to receive a periodical newsletter by email. Please note: you can always deactivate this feature by unsubscribing. Each newsletter contains an unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.
  * You use one of our contact forms because you have a question or want to provide feedback to us. In those cases, you may receive a copy of your message and our reply to your request.
  * You use one of our contact forms to contact a safari company and request a quote for a tour. In those cases, the safari company may email you in reply to your request.
  * If we believe it is vital to contact you and share certain information, we may decide to email you. We will only do so in extraordinary cases such as, for example, when the site or the company holding your personal information is sold and a new owner will govern and safeguard your personal information. Commercial messages or advertising are not considered vital, so we will never use this as an excuse to send spam.

### What information we collect and for what purpose

#### Personal information

We keep the amount of personal information we collect to an absolute minimum and only collect it if strictly necessary or with your consent. You are not obliged to provide your personal information, but this may lead to us not being able to provide you with our services. 

We will not process or store your personal information for any longer than is necessary for the purposes which we collected or processed this information, unless a longer storage period is required by any applicable law or regulation. We process the following information: 

  * **User reviews**  
Upon submitting a user review, we will ask you to provide a screen name (which can be your full name or your first name only) and you will be given the option to provide more info about yourself such as your gender, age, safari experience level, country of residence and photos of your safari. The IP address from where you uploaded the review will also be stored in our databases for spam prevention reasons. We also ask for your email address so that we can contact you in case there is a problem with your review or if other website users have a question about your review. All this info will be publicly visible, except for your IP address and email.

When other users have a question about your review, they can fill out a form that does not reveal your email address and we will forward their question to you by email. In addition, every question that is forwarded to you by email contains an unsubscribe option in case you no longer want other users to be able to ask questions about your review.

It could be that a safari company uses our invite service to send you an email that invites you to review their company on SafariBookings. In that case, your name and email address will be stored in our database to ensure the safari company cannot invite you again for the next 90 days.

Email notifications regarding your review and/or review invite will be sent to you, us and the safari company that is being reviewed. These emails contain your name and email address.

_Storage period:_

    * All personal information associated with a review will be anonymized 90 days after a review has been deleted.
    * Email invites stored in our database will be anonymized after one year.

  * **Quote requests**  
You could decide to use an email form on our website to contact a safari company and request a quote for a tour. These quote requests contain your name, email address, phone number and IP address. Your IP address is stored for spam prevention reasons and will not be shared with the safari company. The quote requests will be emailed directly to the safari company with a copy to you and us. The copy to us will also be stored in our database.

_Storage period:_

    * After two years all personal information associated with a quote request will be anonymized.

  * **Email forms to contact us, SafariBookings**  
You could decide to contact us by email. These emails will be stored in our email inboxes. We can use the email address or other contact information to get back to you in response to your request.

If you use our email forms to report a technical problem with our website we will also collect your IP address for support purposes. The IP address is used to locate your browse session in our log files, which enables us to further investigate the reported problem.

  * **Email Newsletters**  
You may decide to subscribe to one or several of our newsletters in order to periodically receive safari-related news, tips, articles and/or offers by email. When subscribing, your name and email address will be shared with us. Every newsletter that you receive contains an unsubscribe option in case you no longer want to receive these emails.

_Storage period:_

    * If you unsubscribe, you will stop receiving newsletters instantly and your name and email address will be removed from our systems within 90 days.

  * **Your SafariBookings account**  
You may decide to register for a SafariBookings account in order to save your favorites list and/or to become part of our online community.

_Registration_  
You can register your SafariBookings account by either using an email address and password or by using your Facebook or Google login. Your email address will be stored by us to enable you to sign in and gain access to your account and its features. Your password is stored encrypted in such a way that nobody, including us, can access it. Your IP address is processed for spam prevention reasons only.

_Information you share with our community_  
Any information you add to your profile and/or messages (e.g. topics, posts, questions, replies) will be publicly visible and/or shared with the other members of the community. We recommend you don't share personal information about yourself, such as: your full name, address, personal photos or email address; but if you do decide to do so, it is your own responsibility.

_Storage period:_

    * The email address that is linked to your account will be anonymized after you have been inactive for one year, unless you have posted messages that are still online.
    * If you take messages offline, all associated personal information will be anonymized within 90 days.

  * **Log file data**  
As with the majority of web sites you visit, our website and servers employ log files. These log files record non-personally identifiable data, with the exception of IP addresses. The processing of this data will have little or no impact on your privacy. The log files are used to provide insight in the way our site is being used and, if errors occur, log files provide extra insight into what caused the errors and how to fix them.

_Storage period:_

    * Our log files are deleted after 30 days.

#### Computer information

If you use one of the email forms to report a technical problem we will collect non-personally identifiable computer information, such as: the type of browser you are using (e.g. Firefox, Internet Explorer, Google Chrome), the type of operating system you are using (e.g. Windows, Mac OS), the screen or window resolution of your monitor and device type (e.g. PC, iPhone, iPad). We collect this information since it helps us greatly find the problem and it has little or no impact on your privacy. 

#### User Generated Content

User generated content ("user content") is information provided by our users with an intent to be used on our website (e.g. a user review or post on our boards). You, as our user, are responsible for all user content that you submit, post, or otherwise make available to or through our website. We don't claim ownership of user content, but by submitting, posting or otherwise making available to or through our website, you automatically grant us the right to use your user content in any way we desire. This includes the non-exclusive, perpetual, transferable, irrevocable right, with the right of sublicensing and without any royalty or compensation in return, to use, reproduce, adjust, translate, distribute, publish, create derivate works, to disclose and duplicate the content in all now known media and future media. You agree that we can decide if and how your user content is credited and you also agree the user content provided may be indexed by search engines such as Google. You also grant us, and any third party appointed by us, the right to take (legal) actions as it deems necessary for the protection of the (copy)rights of your user content, including, but not by way of limitation, to take (legal) action in the name and on behalf of you. 

#### About children under the age of 16

Our website is not intended for children under the age of 16. We don't knowingly collect personal information from visitors in this age group. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 16, please contact us by sending an email to privacy@safaribookings.com. 

#### Cookies (and tracking scripts or pixels)

Cookies are text files stored in your computer for authenticating, session tracking (state maintenance) and maintaining specific information about the use and users of our website (such as site preferences). Cookie files may also be placed in your computer by our trusted third party companies. For more information about cookies, please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Tracking scripts or pixels consist of a small string of software code that can be used for many purposes, including: site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising auditing and personalization.

We have grouped the cookies we use into three categories; functional cookies, analytical cookies and advertising cookies. Functional cookies are mandatory, but analytical and advertising cookies can be turned off on our [cookie settings page](https://www.safaribookings.com/cookie-settings). Below you will find a complete list of cookies for each category. 

  * **Functional Cookies**  
Functional cookies are either essential to using our website and its features or they allow our website to remember choices you make to give you better functionality and personal features. These cookies do not contain personal information and are not used for analytical or advertising purposes.  Employed By | Cookie Name | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
SafariBookings | XSRF-TOKEN | This security cookie is employed by the Laravel framework – on which our website was built. It protects against cross-site request forgery. | 6 hours  
SafariBookings | laravel_session | The laravel session cookie is used to identify a session instance of a user, which is needed for the website to operate normally. | 6 hours  
SafariBookings | hpp | The ‘homepage photo’ cookie ensures users don’t get to see the same image every time you visit the homepage.  | 30 days  
SafariBookings | hptr | The ‘homepage top rated’ cookie remembers which country was active in the ‘Top Rated Safari Countries’ section. That way the country remains active when you revisit the homepage. | 1 day  
SafariBookings | prf | The ‘preference’ cookie remembers user settings such as where to go, start date and number of travelers. That way users will not have to provide these preferences again when revisiting our website. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | v | The ‘version’ cookie contains the version number of the software that runs our website. It ensures users see the most recent version of our website. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | vsd | The ‘visitor data’ cookie contains geographical information about the user, including country, IP address, region, continent and country calling code. This enables us to personalize the website based on the user’s location. For example, by showing rates in their local currency or pre-filling the country dialing code in web forms.  | 30 days  
SafariBookings | vsd_overrule | The ‘visitor data overrule’ cookie is set when a visitor changes the auto-selected currency in which they want to see the rates on our website. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | enquiry_uid | The ‘enquiry_uid’ cookie protects against spam and forgery. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | list_location | The ‘list location’ cookie saves the last visited page in our directory of tours or tour operators. It enables us to redirect a user back to where they were on our website, before they filled out the quote request form. | 7 days  
SafariBookings | tours__eol | The ‘tours - end of list’ cookie is used for experiments. It indicates that a visitor has reached the end of a list of tours. | 7 days  
SafariBookings | rvw | The ‘review’ cookie is used to enable users to carry the information provided over multiple pages and merge it into a single review.  | 1 day  
SafariBookings | photouploader_rvw | The ‘photouploader review’ cookie enables the upload tool to identify which review the uploaded images belong to. | 1 day  
SafariBookings | oprv | The ‘oprv’ cookie protects against spam and forgery. | 1 year  
SafariBookings | exp | The ‘experiment’ cookie is used for A/B testing and ensures visitors continue to see the version of our website that was selected for them when visiting multiple pages. | 1 year  
SafariBookings | cookie_consent | The ‘cookie consent’ cookie is used to keep track of the cookie consent of visitors. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | disancook | The ‘disable analytical’ cookie is used to keep track of the analytical cookie preferences for visitors. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | disadcook | The ‘disable advertising & social media’ cookie is used to keep track of the advertising & social media cookie preferences for visitors. | 30 days  
SafariBookings | fuid | The ‘fuid’ cookie is used to store a hashed version of the user identifier for the favorites list. | 1 year  
SafariBookings | experts | The ‘experts’ cookie (session storage) keeps a local version of the members of the expert panel. | Until end of session  
SafariBookings | jwplayerLocalId | The ‘jwplayer local ID’ cookie (local storage) is used to store a unique identifier for the video player of JWPlayer. | -  
SafariBookings | jwplayer.volume | The ‘jwplayer volume’ cookie (local storage) is used to remember to volume setting of the visitor for the video player of JWPlayer. | -  
SafariBookings | jwplayer.mute | The ‘jwplayer volume’ cookie (local storage) is used to remember to mute setting of the visitor for the video player of JWPlayer. | -  
SafariBookings | favtour/favoperator* | The ‘favtour/favoperator’ cookies (local storage) are used to keep track of tours and operators that are favorites by the visitor. | -  
SafariBookings | tourclicks | The ‘tourclicks’ cookie (local storage) is used to keep track of clicked tour snippets by the visitor. | -  
SafariBookings | destinations | The ‘destinations’ cookie (local storage) is used to store the last entered destinations in the 'where to' section on the website by the visitor. | -  
  * **Analytical Cookies**  
Analytical cookies are used to gather anonymous information about how our website is used. The insights we draw from this information help us to improve our website.  Employed By | Cookie Name | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
[Google](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/) |  _ga  
_gid  
_gat  
_gac  
_gcl_aw  | These Google cookies collect anonymous information about how people use our website and which website they came from.  
Opt-out of Google Analytics cookies Opt-in for Google Analytics cookies  |  _ga: 2 years  
_gid: 24 hours  
_gat: 1 minute  
_gac: 90 days  
_gcl_aw: 90 days   
[Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) |  _hjUserId  
_hjClosedSurveyInvites  
_hjDonePolls  
_hjMinimizedPolls  
_hjDoneTestersWidgets  
_hjMinimizedTestersWidgets  
_hjIncludedInSample  | These cookies enable Hotjar to collect information about how our website is used and translates that information into anonymized visitor recordings, heatmaps and other types of anonymized reports that help us improve the usability of our website.  
[More info](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/cookie-information) |  All Hotjar cookies: 1 year   
  * **Advertising & Social Media Cookies**  
Advertising cookies enable us to make our advertising campaigns more relevant by customizing them based on your browsing behavior. These cookies also enable us to identify you as a previous visitor to our website on other websites that you visit. This enables us to show you SafariBookings ads and content on those websites.

Social media cookies are set by social media services and may track your browser behavior across our website and other websites, in order to build a profile of your interests. This profile may impact the content and messages you see on other websites.

We always ask for your consent prior to the setting of advertising and social media cookies. 

Employed By | Cookie Name | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
[Bing Ads](https://bingads.microsoft.com/) |  _uetsid  
MR  
MUID  
MUIDB  
Tracking script  | Cookies and scripts employed by Microsoft Bing and used for event tracking, remarketing and profiling.  
[More info](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/audience-targeting/universal-event-tracking) |  _uetsid: 30 min.  
MR: 6 months  
MUID: 1 year  
MUIDB: 2 years  
Script: Unknown   
[Google Ads](https://ads.google.com/intl/en/home/) |  Tracking script  | A script employed by Google Ads and used for event tracking, remarketing and profiling.  
[More info](https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/1722022) |  Unknown   
[Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/) |  Tracking pixel  | A tracking pixel employed by Facebook and used for conversion tracking, remarketing and profiling.  
[More info](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616) |  Unknown   

### Disclosure and/or transfer of data

We keep your personal information confidential and we generally do not disclose it, unless we have your permission hereto, or this is necessary for the performance of a contract, to comply with a legal obligation or for the purposes of our legitimate interests. We may for instance disclose or transfer some of your personal information in the following situations: 

  * When you use an email form on SafariBookings to request a quote from a safari company, we share your message and email address with them. Disclosing this personal information is necessary in order for the safari company to contact you and further discuss the possibility of booking a tour with them.
  * When you subscribe to one or several of our newsletters, we share your email address with MailChimp, our email service provider, in order to send you these newsletters.
  * We may share your personal information with SurveyMonkey to let you participate in a survey or questionnaire.
  * Where necessary we will share your personal information with our third-party providers (e.g. IT providers, CRM providers, marketing service providers, analysts, customer service providers, business development providers and legal service providers) as well as affiliated companies (e.g. parent, sister or daughter companies). They access and use the information on our instructions and on a “need to know” basis only.
  * To host our files and data, including some of your personal information, we make use of certain web and cloud hosting providers, such as Amazon Web Services, Google, and Dropbox.
  * We may share your personal information with certain social media sites for marketing activities.
  * If you have explicitly agreed to the [terms of use](https://www.safaribookings.com/terms-of-use) for our website and we are in the process of selling our company, website or substantial parts of our business, we may disclose and/or transfer your personal information to the (potential) new owner so they can better value our business. If sold, your information will be transferred so that the new owner is able to continue operating this website. This will also be the case if the new owner is a non-EU company, organization or individual.
  * We may also share your personal information to respond to law enforcement requests, court orders or any other legal process or if we believe that such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent or respond to illegal activities, fraud, and physical threats to you or others or as otherwise required by any applicable law or regulation.

Where applicable, we have concluded agreements with our third-party providers to protect your personal data.

Some of these companies may be located in countries outside of the European Economic Area. The companies that are located in the United States are participants of and certified by the [EU US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), which guarantees an adequate level of data protection. For companies in other countries your personal information is safeguarded either because of the European Commission deciding these countries have an adequate level of protection or because your personal information is safeguarded by contractual clauses in the agreements we have with these companies. If you want to receive more information about these safeguards, you can contact us by sending an email to privacy@safaribookings.com. 

### Security measures

We take strict security measures to protect personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. These measures include limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers as well as electronic security systems, data encryption and password protections, which guard against unauthorized access. 

### Control over your data

You are entitled to object to us processing your personal data. You may also access your information, ask us for an overview of your information or ask for a copy. You may also request us to correct or delete certain data, restrict processing of your data, or ask us to transfer some of this information to you or other organizations. In some cases you may object to the processing of your data and, where we have asked for your consent to process personal data, you can withdraw this consent at any time. If the processing is solely based on your consent, we will not process your personal information any longer. Where we process your data for our legitimate interests, you can contact us if you want more information about these.

There are some exceptions to these rights. For example, it will not be possible for us to delete your data if we are required by law to keep it or if we hold it in connection with a contract with you. Similarly, access to your data may be refused if making the information available would reveal personal information about another person or if we are legally prevented from disclosing such information. We will always inform you if we will not comply with your request for any reason whatsoever.

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us using the details below.

We will provide you with information on action taken on your request within one month after receiving this request. Depending on the complexity and number of requests we may extend this period by two further months, in which case we will also inform you. 

### Contacting us, questions and complaints

SafariBookings B.V. is the controller of your personal information. Questions, comments, requests or complaints concerning this privacy notice and the way we process your personal information are welcomed and can be addressed to us at [privacy@safaribookings.com](mailto:privacy@safaribookings.com) or Veemarktkade 8 (Unit 6249), 5222AE ‘s-Hertogenbosch, the Netherlands, Europe.

If you have a complaint about the way we handle your personal data, you also have the right to address this with the data protection authority of the country in which you live or work, or the country in which we are located. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

We are – at all times – entitled to change the way we collect, transmit and process personal information and such other information as we may deem necessary and at our sole discretion. We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time in order to reflect the latest amendments. As soon as this page is updated the changes become effective. Please review this privacy policy periodically.
